scr5173@psu.edu (814) 243-3762

## SAMUEL ROBERTSON

http://robertsonsamuel.github.io

6705 204th St SW, Unit B-101, Lynnwood, WA 98036

## PERSONAL BIO

Mechanical engineer with 2 years of formal and trained sales experience. I am a technology enthusiast with a passion of sharing the benefits of it with others. I want the customer to experience why they need our services and how we can improve their workflow and business operations.

## **EDUCATION**

The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, State College, PA

05/2011 - 08/2015

Bachelor of Science (B.S) Mechanical Engineering GPA: 2.9/4.0

IES Study Abroad Graduate- Tokyo, Japan

05/2013 - 07/2013

Study Abroad: Japanese Language and Art

# **EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE**

**Delphi Automotive PLC-Internship,** 200 Upper Mountain Rd, Lockport, NY 14094

05/2014 - 08/2014

- Implemented prototype HVAC systems into existing vehicles using SolidWorks and 3D scans of components for testing to meet customer contract performance evaluation.
- Created a test method for a newer, cheaper, front-of-dash seal. Cost was lowered per seal used per vehicle on each HVAC unit.
- Solved low flow measurement issues in side window ducting by using numerical analysis and real-world data.

### Best Buy- Sales Associate, 430 Town Centre Dr. Johnstown, PA 15904

06/2011 - 09/2013

- Aided the GeekSquad in PC repair and diagnosis; created custom solutions for customers.
- Used selling skills to create friendly and professional environments for customers while maximizing profit and service satisfaction.

# TEAMWORK BASED PROJECTS

### **Ingersoll Rand Senior Project**

01/2015 - 05/2015

- Worked remotely with students from Shanghai Jiao Tong University and Ingersoll Rand to develop, design and test using computer models, a new shell and tube heat exchanger.
- Project Manager for a team of 6; assisted in each aspect of the product development and also ensured a steady pace of progression using Microsoft Project, and Slack for communication.

### **Facet Water Turbine Junior Project**

01/2013 - 05/2013

- Created a water powered electric generation turbine prototype that provides 2.11V and 0.44 watts of power across a  $10\Omega$  load resistor.
- Leader of a team of 4 to create two alpha and one beta prototype units for the project.

# Relevant Skills

### **Applicable Skills**

- Formal Sales training from the Best Buy Co.
- Adept knowledge of Virtual Machines, computer hardware and storage mediums.
- Comfortable in UNIX environments, network protocols, SSH, DNS, Dynamic and Static IPs.
- An understanding of web technologies and web development.
- Great amount of experience working with foreign customers.
- Proposal and consolidation experience from the Ingersoll Rand project.